Garnet J. Knights Papers, 1927-1986
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Garnet J. Knights papers
1927-1986
1962-1983
Knights, Garnet J., 1900-1985
MS 291
1 box (.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
YWCA overseas official. Material reflects a small portion of Knights' professional life. Includes photographs (YWCA), information generated by the YWCA, tributes given at her memorial service, and reminiscences she wrote of her service in Uruguay. Much of the correspondence is in Spanish, although there are brief translations attached to some of the letters.
Garnet J. Knights was born November 21, 1900, and received a BA from Oberlin College and an MA from New York University. She joined the staff of the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) and was a physical education instructor in Uruguay from 1927 to 1931, followed by service as Director of Health, Physical Education and Recreation at the Syracuse, NY, YWCA. In 1942 she went to Mexico as Director of Physical Education and was their U.S. Advisory Secretary. Returning to New York in 1963, she worked with Chinese Americans at the China Institute in New York City. Knights retired to Foulkeways residential retirement community in Gwynedd, PA, in 1971 where she directed the physical fitness program. She died there November 30, 1985.
The Garnet J. Knights Papers consist of three linear inches (1 document box) of material reflecting a small portion of her professional life. The biographical material consists of information generated by the YWCA, tributes given at her memorial service, and reminiscences she wrote of her service in Uruguay. Much of the correspondence is in Spanish, although there are brief translations attached to some of the letters. All correspondence (incoming and outgoing) has been filed together and arranged chronologically. There are some third party letters which were evidently routed to Knights by others. The YWCA series includes eleven original photographs and photocopies of three photographs. Some are identified, the rest are not.
This collection is organized into three series:
I. Biographical
II. Correspondence
III. YWCA
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
They are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any added restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Garnet Knights papers were a gift of the archives of the National Board of the YWCA in 1991.
Search Terms
Knights, Garnet J., 1900-1985; Mexico--Description and travel--Sources; Uruguay--Description and travel--Sources; Physical education for women--History--Sources; Young Women's Christian Associations--Uruguay--History; Young Women's Christian Associations--Mexico--History
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL
  - Biographical material: Tributes, reminiscences, YWCA records, 1953-86 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1976-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- SERIES III. YWCA
  - Miscellaneous printed material and notes, 1962-79 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1927-63 (Box 1, Folder 7)